我是奧利弗•奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年裡  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友  我只能偽裝成另一個人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
深切懷念托馬斯•梅林
孝子
成為另一種存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
你能說你沒有濫用藥物嗎
You're telling me you don't have a substance abuse problem?
地檢辦給了一筆很可觀的解雇補償金
The D.A.'s office has a generous severance package.
等等  我去跟檢察官親自解釋一下好嗎
Wait, let me explain to the D.A.--
對不起  但是你被解雇了
I'm sorry, but you're done.
是時候做出選擇了  奧利弗
Time to choose, Oliver,
選出誰生  誰死
who lives and who dies.
你拿到了你想要的東西
You got what you came for!
-時間到  -你這變態的神經病
- Time's up. - You freaking psychopath!
不  不
No, no!
不
No!
羅伊被注射了血清
Roy was injected with the serum.
我們得看著他
We are going to have to keep an eye on him.
羅伊  停下  他快死了
Roy! Stop it, you're killing him!
現在你更快更強了
You're stronger, you heal faster,
但是你卻控制不了自己
but you're not in control.
我可以教你  讓我幫你吧
I can teach you. Let me help you.
我們什麼時候開始
When do we start?
給你帶來個新客人
Got your latest customer.
這位天才竟然去搶
Genius who held up the convenience store
警局對面的便利店
across the street from a police precinct.
這計劃可不明智
Not the smartest plan.
走過來
Come on through.
膝蓋有傷
Bum knee.
幾年前動過手術
I had it replaced a few years ago.
那還是用老辦法吧
Well, I guess we'll have to do this old-fashioned-like.
抬起胳膊
Arms up.
給你找了個新獄友
Got your new bunk mate.
別惹事
Play nice.
你是本•特納嗎
Ben Turner?
今晚
Tonight.
午夜  紅林路和燕草大道
Midnight. Redwood Drive and Larkspur Avenue.
你在說什麼
What the hell are you talking about?
紅林路和燕草大道  屋頂  去那裡
Redwood and Larkspur. The rooftop. Be there.
你沒四下看看嗎
I don't know if you've looked around,
我們沒法自由出入這地方
but we don't exactly have in and out privileges here.
我兒子跟他媽在一起
My son is with his mother.
反正我是再也見不到他了
I won't get to see him, anyway.
這樣做  他就沒事
This way, he's set.
我完成這事  他就能拿到錢
I do this, he gets the money.
完成什麼
Do what?
這裡怎麼回事
What's going on down there?
該死
Crap.
你把他怎麼了
What the hell did you do to him?
我什麼也沒做
I didn't do anything.
綠   箭   俠
第二季第十二集
再來
Again.
我昨天是在拍水
You know, I slapped water out of a bowl yesterday.
前天也是在拍水
And I slapped water out of a bowl the day before.
你肯定很擅長了
You must be getting pretty good at it.
是啊  我已經等不及被狗糧攻擊了
Yeah, well, I can't wait to get attacked by a dog dish.
這是射手鍛煉臂力的方法
This is how an archer builds arm strength.
你難道不知道嗎
I'm not sure if you've been paying attention,
力量對我來說不是問題
but strength isn't my problem.
對  但控制力量是你的問題
No, controlling it is.
再來
Again.
就因為這樣
And that...
你上周才把一個人打到進醫院
is how you put a guy in the hospital last week.
你怎麼知道的
How'd you know about that?
這事跟你沒關係
It's none of your business.
你答應讓我幫你的時候
You made it my business
這事就跟我有關係了
when you agreed to let me help you.
我以前認識一個像你這樣的人
I knew someone like you.
注射了米拉庫魯的人
Someone injected with the Mirakuru.
他是我的朋友
He was my friend.
但是這血清扭曲了他的心智
But it warped his mind to the point
以至於我都認不出他了
where I didn't even recognize him anymore.
這人是誰
Who was this guy?
我怎麼從沒聽說過他
How come I've never heard of him?
也沒聽說過米拉庫魯
Or that Mirakuru?
還有什麼他的事你能告訴我嗎
Is there anything you can tell me about him?
是的
Yeah.
我用一支箭射穿了他的眼
I had to put an arrow through his eye.
如果我沒看錯的話  斯萊德在洞裡
If I'm reading this right, then Slade is back at the cave.
他為什麼要去墓地那裡
Well, why would he go back to where the graves are?
找到他就知道了
We'll find out when we find him.
找到他的時候  你不能跟他說
And when we do... you can't tell him.
說什麼
Tell him what?
別對我像個外人似的
Don't talk to me like I'm other people.
你臉上就是這種表情
You've got that look on your face.
我們第一次接吻時就是這種表情
The same one that you had after the first time we kissed.
純粹內疚的表情
Pure guilt.
因為我就是很內疚  莎拉
Because I am guilty, Sara.
因為我  艾沃才殺了莎朵
Ivo killed Shado because of me.
不是這樣的
But that's not true.
就算是這樣
And even if it was,
你告訴斯萊德是因為你
nothing good comes from telling Slade
害死了他愛的女人
that you think you're responsible
對你沒有任何好處
for the death of the woman he loved.
愛是最強大的情感
Love's the most powerful emotion.
因此它也是最危險的
And that makes it the most dangerous.
說得真好
Great.
你知道怎麼去洞穴嗎
You still know how to get to the cave?
是的
Yeah.
這條路
It's this way.
西婭
Thea?
你怎麼在家
What are you doing home?
我以為你留在羅伊家了
I thought you were staying at Roy's.
我想自己待一會
Just needed a little "me" Time.
怎麼穿得這麼隆重
What's with the fancy fancy?
我  我要出去吃飯
Oh, I'm-- I'm going out to dinner.
跟沃爾特一起
With Walter.
算是約會嗎
Like a date?
只是吃晚飯
Like a dinner.
說實話  我也不知道今晚算什麼
Truly, I don't know what the evening holds.
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
是的  我沒事
Yeah. I'm fine.
主要是
Mostly. Uh...
羅伊的事
It's Roy.
他上周遇上點麻煩
He had some trouble last week, and...
而我不知道怎麼幫他
I don't know how to help him.
你想讓我留在家裡嗎
Do you want me to stay home?
我可以給沃爾特打個電話  重新再約
I can call Walter and we can reschedule.
當然不用
Absolutely not.
如果你和沃爾特準備重歸於好
If you and Walter are going to patch things up...
不給你壓力  但你一定要去
No pressure. But you're going.
可能沒什麼
It may be nothing.
只有一個辦法才能知道
Only one way to find out.
不介意  老爸  進來吧
No, please, dad, come right in.
看來你已經把房子住得很破爛了
Well, I guess you're going for that lived-in look.
沒有工作請不起管家
Can't afford a housekeeper without a job.
酒錢倒是挺足的
Got enough beverage money, I see.
如果你想吵架
I'm going to need to crack
那就先讓我再開一瓶酒吧
open another bottle if we're going to fight.
我不是來吵架的
I didn't come here to fight.
那你來幹什麼
Then why are you here?
我過得挺好的  真的
Because I'm fine, really.
實際上  我有個工作面試
In fact, I have a job interview.
是喬安娜的新公司
At Joanna's new firm.
挺好的  不錯
That's good. Good.
但我來這裡的真正原因是
But the real reason I came here is--
是你覺得你需要每週定量的來
Is because you realized that you didn't reach your weekly quota
揭示我的生活如何不堪
of reminding me of how much I'm ruining my life?
是因為我想你了  勞蕾爾
It's 'cause I miss you, Laurel.
長久以來  我們相依為命
For a long time, it was just you and me.
不管發生什麼
Whatever else was going on,
不管對方有多糟糕
no matter how bad either of us was doing,
我們誰都不會不管對方
we didn't disappear on each other.
你是我的家人
Because you're my family.
而我想念我的家人
And I miss my family.
所以要不要一起吃個晚餐
So how about we have dinner?
你和我  今晚
You and me, tonight.
我已經吃過了
I already ate.
好吧
Yeah.
那明晚呢
How about tomorrow night?
可以
Sure.
明晚晚餐
Dinner tomorrow.
謝謝
Thank you.
和羅伊怎麼樣了
How's it going with Roy?
不怎麼樣
Not well!
我跟這孩子不熟
I don't know the kid all too well,
但是他看起來充滿了憤怒
but he seems to be five kinds of angry.
你低估他了
You might be underestimating.
羅伊在注射米拉庫魯前就很憤青了
Roy was mad at the world before he was injected with Mirakuru.
你說你有過類似經歷
You say you've seen this before?
斯萊德•威爾遜  他曾是我朋友
Slade Wilson. He was my friend.
你故意使用了過去時
Troubling use of past tense there.
我覺得我可以幫助他控制住
I thought I could help him control it.
但我錯了
I was wrong.
但是現在我知道的更多了  我不會在
But I know more now, and I'm not going
羅伊身上犯同樣的錯誤了
to make the same mistake with Roy.
是什麼
What's that?
鐵山監獄  鑒於他們那可悲的安保能力
Iron Heights. Due to their low security post-quake,
我覺得應該花些時間監視一下
I thought it would be a good idea to keep an eye on
他們的內部通訊系統
their internal communication for a while.
你黑進了監獄內部系統
You hacked into a prison system network?
你是在批判我嗎
Is that judgment I'm hearing?
驕傲
Pride.
鐵山監獄剛對本•特納下了通牒
Iron Heights just put out a bolo for Ben Turner,
也就是青銅虎  順便說一句
Aka Bronze Tiger, which, btw,
這真是個爛綽號  老虎不是青銅色的
is a terrible nickname, because tigers are not bronze.
特納逃跑了
Turner escaped?
出去時殺了十個守衛
Killed ten guards on his way out.
這事肯定會上新聞
You think that would have made the news.
鐵山監獄保密的能力
Iron Heights is better at keeping secrets
比他們看管囚犯的能力強多了
than they are at keeping prisoners.
知道他可能去哪嗎
Any idea where he's headed?
不知道
No.
找出來
Get one.
叫你們的人到別處去
Tell your men to take a walk.
走開
Leave us.
武器可以放在這
They can leave their weapons, too.
感謝您的提前釋放
Thank you for the early release.
本來想就這麼走的  但是我
Thought about taking off, but I'm...
很好奇
curious.
誰會幫個陌生人逃獄啊
Who would break a stranger out of prison?
想讓那罪犯幫忙的人
Someone who wishes to hire you for a job.
我需要幫忙找回一樣東西
I need you to help my men retrieve a certain item.
就是這個
This is the item.
你見過  對吧
You know it, yes?
確實
Yes, I do.
你知道還缺什麼嗎
Do you know what you're missing with here?
不菲的價格
Won't be cheap.
錢不是問題
This is not a problem.
你知道它有百人以上的殺傷力吧
You do know that thing could kill hundreds of people?
不對  特納先生
No, Mr. Turner.
是千人以上
It will kill thousands.
該你了
Now you.
慢慢來
Go slowly.
停
Stop!
我不是在教你出拳
This is not about learning to throw a punch,
是在教你力度控制
this is about learning to control your strength.
先是打水花  現在又是這個
First water slapping, now this.
你什麼時候才能玩完這些
When are you going to run out of ways
讓我看起來很蠢的把戲
to make me look stupid?!
我能學到的就只有怎麼被惹毛
All I'm learning is new ways to get pissed off,
順便說一句
and in case you haven't noticed,
我本來就擅長被惹毛
I'm already pretty good at that.
憤怒並非無益  羅伊  力量就來自憤怒
There's nothing wrong with anger, Roy. Anger is energy,
但是你得學習用好的方式使用它
but you need to learn to channel it in a positive way.
比如打擊那些破壞城市的人
Like putting the hurt on guys going after the city.
就不讓我打個能反擊的目標嗎
Let me try hitting something that'll actually hit back.
時候未到
Too soon.
帶我去一次
Get me out there with you.
就一晚上
One night.
這些蠢東西也能好接受些
All this, it would be a lot easier to take.
莫伊拉
Moira.
我以為是二人晚餐呢
Ah. I didn't realize we'd have company.
這位是馬克•法蘭西斯
This is Mark Frances.
他是卡達克集團的首席財務官
Mark's CFO at Kardak Holdings.
我們曾在政黨選舉指導委員會共事過
We've been putting in some hours with the party's election steering committee.
很高興見到你
It's a pleasure to meet you.
最近高興見我的人可不多了
Those are words I'm not accustomed to hearing these days.
你只是像母獅一樣在保護自己的孩子們
You were a lioness doing what she had to do to protect her cubs.
星城很多人都像我一樣
You know, I'm not the only person in Starling
站在你這邊
who sees it that way.
謝謝你的安慰
That's a comfort.
實話實說而已  請坐
It's the truth. Please.
謝謝
Thank you.
不常見你對政治
Well, it's unlike you to
如此興趣濃厚呢  沃爾特
show such an interest in politics, Walter.
這是我星城國家銀行新工作的一部分
It's part of my new position at the Starling National Bank.
董事會很關注
My board of directors is very concerned
星城的發展方向
about the trajectory of the city.
-你是說塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德  -是的
- You mean Sebastian Blood. - Yeah.
我們相信他的政策會讓
We believe that his policies will bankrupt Starling
星城在八個月之內破產
within the next eight months.
但平常選民卻不關注此事
Not that the average voter cares.
他們都被他的魅力俘獲了
They're all caught up in his charisma.
而且沒有可以與他匹敵的對手
And he's not running against a viable opponent.
他打敗了我們所有重點培養的候選人
Blood's trounced every potential candidate we've focus-tested.
不過制度方面是他的弱項
But we believe that he's vulnerable on regulation.
就算是又能怎樣呢
Even if he is, it hardly matters.
銀行政策只是證交會的問題
Banking regulations are an SEC issue.
星城需要的是城市層面的對抗
Starling City needs to use the means at a city's disposal.
沃爾特說過你很聰明
Walter said you were smart.
但你沒邀請我吃晚餐  聽我的意見
But you didn't invite me to dinner to hear my opinions.
你想瞭解我的位置
You want to hear my positions.
你想讓我去對抗塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德
You want me to run against Sebastian Blood.
爸  我快餓死了  我們要去哪兒
Dad, I'm starving. Where are we going?
就在這兒有個小店
It's little hole in the wall right here.
勞蕾爾  等一下
Laurel, wait.
別碰我
Don't touch me.
我真不敢相信你會做這樣的事情
I can't believe you would do something like this.
否則你也不會來呀
Well, you wouldn't have come otherwise.
你說對了
Well, you got that right.
勞蕾爾  你需要幫助
Laurel, you need help.
那也用不著他們
Not from them.
那間屋子裡沒有一個人
There is not one person in that room
知道我所經歷的痛苦
who knows what I have been through.
你說的沒錯  他們之中有人承受過比你更痛苦的事情
Yeah, you're right. Some of them, they've been through worse.
但是不管怎樣
But for better or worse,
每一個人走進那間屋子都是因為需要
everyone in that room needs to be there,
現在你也需要去那
and you need to be there.
你以為只有你失去過愛人嗎
You think you're the only person that's ever lost someone?
只有你被炒過魷魚  只有你曾經把生活搞的一團糟嗎
Who ever got fired, who ever got their lives into a mess?
孩子  你好好想想  不是只有你最慘
You think again, kiddo, 'cause you're not.
你看  現在我們已經來了
Now, look, we're here now.
那你為什麼不能呆一會兒呢
So why don't you just stay for a bit?
你不需要跟別人說你的事  你只需要傾聽
You don't have to share or talk. You just listen.
我已經說的很清楚了
I thought I made myself clear.
我餓了
I'm hungry.
我還是一個人去吃飯吧
And now I think I'll eat alone.
說吧
Go ahead.
星城警署網站剛剛公佈了一起謀殺案
SCPD's network just lit up with a fresh homicide,
死者身上有多處刺傷  像是爪子弄的
Multiple stab wounds. Like claw marks.
受害人是一名建築師
The victim was an architect.
特納洗劫了他的住所  拿走了他設計的圖紙
Turner ransacked his place; took blueprints of his designs.
他是馬爾科姆•梅林的房子的設計者之一
One of the aforementioned designs--Malcolm Merlyn's house.
我對建築學不太瞭解  但我知道這不是好事
I don't know much about architecture, but this can't be good.
特納想從梅林的房子得到什麼
What would Turner want with Merlyn's house?
現在還不清楚  馬爾科姆的所有產業
Not sure yet. All of Malcolm's holdings,
包括那棟房子  都處於破產受管狀態
including the house, are in receivership.
你在和誰講話
Who's that you're talking to?
等等  讓我猜猜  這個你也不能告訴我
Oh, wait, let me guess, you can't tell me that, either.
一個被我送進監獄的人越獄了
A guy that I put in prison got out,
而我知道他會去哪
and I have an idea where he's headed.
你有連帽衫嗎
Do you have one of your hoodies?
這還用問嗎
Do you seriously have to ask?
無論發生什麼事  無論遇到什麼人
Whatever happens, whoever we run into,
都不要理會
do not engage.
什麼也不要碰
And don't touch anything.
這是他的孩子  對嗎
This is his kid, right?
死掉的那個人的孩子
The guy that died?
是
Yes.
你很熟悉這裡
You know your way around this place.
你之前來過這兒嗎
You been here before?
那是什麼
What was that?
聲音是從地下傳出來的
It came from underground.
梅林有一個大的地下車庫
Merlyn has a large garage.
咱們走
Let's go.
這到底是什麼
What the hell is that?
看起來像個原型機
Looks like a prototype.
什麼的原型機
Of what?
一個曾經殺死了503個人的機器的原型機
A machine that killed 503 people.
梅林自己的地震設備
Merlyn's own earthquake device.
好了  如探囊取物般簡單
Ok, a simple snatch and grab.
不明白為什麼阿米蒂奇先生要讓你跟著
Don't know why Mr. Armitage thought we needed you.
因為他們
For that.
離那臺設備遠點
Step away from the device.
你們不知道你們拿的是什麼
You don't know what it is you're dealing with.
不就是一臺能製造地震的大機器嗎
Big machine, makes earthquakes?
如果它落到居心不良的人手中
Do you have any idea what happens
你知道會發生什麼事嗎
if the wrong people have it?
知道  我收錢了
Yeah. I get paid.
關好門
Close it up.
那臺機器殺了我8個朋友
That thing killed eight of my friends.
夠了
That's enough!
你看起來很生氣
Uh-oh. You got angry face.
發生了什麼事
What happened?
羅伊•哈珀
Roy Harper.
你帶他出去了
You took him out in the field--
狄格爾  他沒聽我的話
He wasn't listening to me, Diggle!
我試圖要抓住他  但他失去了控制
I'm trying to reach him, but he lost control.
他差點殺了人
Then he nearly killed somebody,
我當然不能讓他這麼幹  在這過程中
which I obviously couldn't let happen, and in the process--
特納跑了
Turner got away.
他去那偷什麼  梅林的藝術收藏品嗎
What was he there to steal? Merlyn's art collection?
比那要危險的多的東西
Something much more dangerous.
是一臺地震機的樣機
It's a prototype earthquake machine.
天吶
Oh, holy god.
為什麼特納要毀掉這座城市
Why would Turner want to destroy the city?
他沒有  他是一個雇傭兵
He doesn't. He's a mercenary
他為出價最高的人服務
Selling his services to the highest bidder.
這塊表是其中一個
This watch belonged to one of the guys
-和特納一起工作的人的  -有指紋
- Turner was working with. - Fingerprints.
特納是個獨行者  這意味著手錶的主人為特納的客戶工作
Turner's a loner, which mean that guy works for his client.
有了指紋就等於知道了名字  等於知道了他的同夥
Fingerprints equals name, equals known associates.
我馬上查
I'm on it.
在羅伊眼中看到的神情
It was the look in Roy's eyes.
和斯萊德眼中的一模一樣
It was Slade all over again.
奧利弗  斯萊德發生了什麼事
Oliver, what happened with Slade?
我
Me.
有人殺了莎朵
Someone killed Shado.
斯萊德愛過莎朵  而這是我的錯
Slade loved Shado, and it was my fault.
我想要告訴他
I wanted to tell him,
因為這從我口中說出比較好
because it would have been better coming from me,
但是我沒有
but I didn't.
然後  他從其他途徑知道了
And he found out another way.
如果我直接告訴了他真相
If I had just told him the truth,
我可能已經得到了他的諒解
I could have gotten through to him.
而這就是為什麼  對你來說得到羅伊的諒解很重要
And that's why it's so important for you to get through to Roy.
我做了5年的噩夢
I lived a five year nightmare.
但如果我學到了什麼
But if I learn something
讓我現在能夠瞭解羅伊
that could help me reach Roy now...
那所有的一切就都值得
it'll all be worth it.
他不在這兒
He's not here.
那他能去哪兒  我們已經檢查過飛機了
Where else could he be? We already checked the plane.
我不知道
I don't know.
你記得之前見過這些嗎
Do you remember seeing these before?
我沒四處看過
I didn't really look around.
這些看起來很眼熟
They look familiar.
這可能是煉獄島
This could be Lian Yu.
不  我是說這些演算
No, I mean the calculations.
我之前見過
I've seen those before.
可能是你第一次進山洞見到的
Maybe the first time you were in the cave.
我不這麼認為
I don't think so.
-法爾斯的發射器  -什麼
- Fyer's launcher. - What?
去年有部隊來過這個島
Oh, there were soldiers on the island last year,
他們有一個導彈發射器  他們演示時
And they had a missile launcher. I saw one of these
我看到過其中一個   他們在進行發射計算
on the display. They're firing calculations...
他想要把那炸掉
He's going to blow it up.
把什麼炸掉
Blow what up?
貨船
The freighter.
謝天謝地你在這  我需要你幫忙
Oh, thank god you're here, I need your help--
我有話要跟你說  這很重要
I have to talk to you. It's important.
好  你看起來糟透了  沒什麼事吧
Ok. You look stressed out, is everything ok?
你得離開星城
You have to leave town.
可以的話  帶上你媽跟你哥  現在就離開
Grab your mother and your brother, if you can, and leave.
幾天就好
It's just for a few days.
能給個解釋嗎
A reason would be nice.
你得相信我  西婭
I need you to trust me, Thea.
我相信你  只是
I do. I just--
我們怎麼能無緣無故就全家人離開呢
I can't up and leave with my family without a reason.
但你必須走
No, you have to.
羅伊  你說的我完全聽不懂
Roy, you're not making any sense right now.
能告訴我到底發生了什麼事嗎
Would you just tell me what's going on?
你怎麼不聽我說呢
Why aren't you listening to me?
你得聽我說
I need you to listen to me!
羅伊  你弄疼我了
Roy, you're hurting me!
我不是...不是...
I didn't...I didn't...
不是有意的  對不起
I didn't mean to. I'm sorry.
我知道
I know!
離開創新聯合會後
Well. Your work environment
你的工作環境真是提高了不少
has definitely improved since CNRI.
這地方比我公寓還大呢
This place is bigger than my apartment!
不過外表的光鮮也是有局限的
Well, there is a limit to the glamour, unfortunately.
我整天都在處理文件
I spend my days in document production--
回答問詢
and answering interrogatories.
感覺都不像是跟法律相關
It doesn't feel like practicing law so much as
而是做文書了
pushing papers.
如果我不瞭解的話  還真會以為
If I didn't know any better, I'd think
你是要說服我不幹這份工作呢
that you were trying to talk me out of the job here.
看來我還是有點自知
I guess I do know better.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎麼回事
What's going on?
這裡的一位合夥人
One of the partners serves
是律師協會紀律委員會成員
on the Bar Association's Disciplinary Committee,
我把你的簡歷遞上去時
and...well, when I sent your resume,
他做了些背景調查
he did some checking.
那完全是個誤會
That was a complete misunderstanding.
沒錯  我是遇到了點麻煩
I mean, sure, yeah, I had some problems,
但我現在沒事了
but I'm fine now.
律師協會要進行紀律聽證會
The bar is going to open disciplinary proceedings.
為什麼
What for?
確定你是否還有能力繼續做律師
Conduct affecting your fitness to practice.
這真是  真是太荒謬了
That's-- that's ridiculous.
我知道
I know.
但在這事塵埃落地前
But while this is out there,
事務所不能雇傭你
the firm can't hire you.
謝謝
Thanks.
謝謝你告訴我  我得走了
Thanks for letting me know. I have to go.
勞蕾爾  勞蕾爾
Laurel, Laurel.
你能度過這難關的  明白嗎
You can fight this, ok?
我會幫助你
I'll help you, and--
我需要點時間來理清頭緒
I need some time to...process.
我再打給你
I'll call you.
給你來點什麼喝的
Can I fix you a drink?
跟你一樣就行
Whatever you're having.
那晚上見到你很開心  莫伊拉
It was good to see you the other night, Moira.
的確不錯
It was lovely.
我好久沒這麼開心地笑過了
It's been a while since I've had such a good laugh.
我們不是在說笑  莫伊拉
It was no joke, Moira.
馬克說的是實話
Mark was telling the truth.
星城的很多人都覺得
A significant number of people in Starling City
你幫馬爾科姆•梅林做事
feel that your actions with Malcolm Merlyn
是為了保護你的家人
were justified to protect your family.
事實上有43.6%的人這麼認為
43.6%, in fact.
你對我發起民意測驗
You polled people about me?
這是挑選候選人的
Prudent course of action when vetting
謹慎之舉  沒錯
a potential candidate, yes.
星城有六十萬人
600,000 people in Starling City.
我覺得你應該能找到一個
I'd think you could find someone not responsible
沒用地震機毀壞它的人來競選
for destroying it with an earthquake machine.
可你名聲在外
Not with your name recognition.
我們需要一個能力挽狂瀾的候選人  莫伊拉
We need a game change candidate, Moira.
而星城沒有人比你更德高望重了
And there's no one in Starling with a higher profile than you.
查爾斯•曼森也挺有名的
Charles Manson is rather well-known,
曼森家族曾在加州領導著臭名昭著犯罪團夥
-可沒人會投票給他  -沒錯
- and no one is going to vote for him. - True.
同樣選民也喜歡自我救贖的故事
Equally true, voters like redemption stories.
比爾•克林頓  艾略特•斯皮策[前紐約市長]
Bill Clinton, Elliot Spitzer,
兩人均被性醜聞纏身
瑪莎•史都華
Martha Stewart.
美國家政女神 曾因內幕交易被判自家中軟禁五個月
她可沒參加過競選
Oh, I don't believe she ran for office.
但如果她參加了  肯定會贏的
But if she had, she would have won.
會贏什麼
Would have won what?
西婭
Ah, Thea.
怎麼了
Mmm, what's going on?
我在勸你媽媽參加市長競選
I'm just convincing your mother to run for mayor.
什麼市長
Of what?
看到了吧
You see?
親愛的  你還好吧
Sweetheart, are you all right?
你真的別再問這問題了
You really need to stop asking that.
你是認真的嗎
Are you serious?
我也知道這很難相信
It's hard to believe, I know.
不  並不是
No. No, it's not.
這其實會是我有投票權後的第一回競選
Look, this is actually the first election I can vote in,
作為一個新手選民
and...as a newly minted voter,
我覺得這主意也不算太瘋狂
I don't think it sounds that crazy.
聽聽你寶貝女兒說的話
From out of the mouths of babes.
你來晚了
You're late.
我想要我女朋友離開星城
I tried to get my girlfriend to leave town.
但她不肯
But she won't.
不準把她牽扯進來
You cannot bring her into this.
可我要怎麼一邊隱瞞著她
But how am I supposed to lie to her
一邊保護她呢
and protect her at the same time?
你是怎麼做到的
How do you do it?
你怎麼對你生活中的人隱瞞事實真相
How do you keep secrets from people in your life?
只要記住這是唯一保證他們安全的辦法
By remembering it's the only way to keep them safe.
不  要讓他們安全才能保證安全
No, keeping them safe is what keeps them safe.
該告訴他們真相
Telling people the truth.
可你什麼都不願跟我說
But you, you won't tell me anything.
不說米拉庫魯  還有那個傢伙
Not about the Mirakuru, and this other guy.
卻讓我在這傻子一樣拍水跟打木頭人
And you got me slapping water and hitting dummies instead.
羅伊  你現在太激動了  需要冷靜下來
Roy, you're spiraling and you need to calm down.
不  我需要去救西婭
No. I need to save Thea.
都是因為你那傢伙才跑出去了
That thing is out in the open because of you.
你幫的忙夠多了
I think you've done enough.
放開我
Let go of me.
-羅伊  -我說了放開我
- Roy... - I said let go of me!
控制一下你自己
Get control.
就算不為我  不為你自己
If not for me or yourself,
也為了西婭
then do it for Thea.
你他媽對西婭有什麼瞭解
What the hell do you know about Thea?
別跟我說她
Don't you talk about her!
你鬧夠了沒
Are you done?
不  我沒夠
No. I'm not done.
我要去阻止那傢伙
I'm going to stop this thing.
你要是想阻止我  就試試
And if you want to stop me, try.
再給我一箭  來啊
Try putting another arrow in me. Go ahead.
我現在恢復得很快  但如果你擋我的路
'Cause I heal fast now. But you get in my way,
我就讓你好好看看你所擔心的
then I'll give you a good look at that anger you're so worried
我失去控制發怒會怎樣
about me losing control of.
我說我們應該在這下麵裝一臺X光機的時候
You both scoffed when I said we should invest
你們倆都嘲笑我
in an x-ray machine for down here.
你想要怎麼處理羅伊
What do you want to do about Roy?
指紋查的怎麼樣了
Where are we with the fingerprint?
我略過了國內的機構
I struck out on domestic agencies,
現在在查國際刑警  中國公安
but I'm checking Interpol, PRC Public Security
以及俄羅斯內務部的數據庫
and MVD databases now.
奧利弗  我知道你要幫羅伊  也知道為什麼
Oliver, I know you've taken Roy on, and why,
但是羅伊  斯萊德  很多我共事過的人...
but Roy, Slade, a lot of guys I've served with...
有些人已經喪失心智了  夥計
Some people are just broken, man.
無藥可救了
And nobody can put them back together.
我拒絕相信這些
I refuse to believe that.
我不會讓發生在斯萊德身上的事
I'm not letting what happened
再發生到羅伊身上
to Slade happen to Roy.
我不會的
I'm not.
怎麼了
Yeah.
你在俱樂部附近嗎
Are you near the club?
離得很近  怎麼了
I'm pretty close. Why?
勞蕾爾在這裡
Laurel's here.
她看起來不太好
She doesn't look good.
勞蕾爾在樓上
Hey. Laurel's upstairs.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
能給我杯帶橄欖的飲料嗎
Can I get something with olives?
什麼飲料無所謂  只要有很多橄欖就行
I don't care what it is, as long as there are a lot of olives.
咖啡怎麼樣
How about coffee?
咖啡和橄欖
Coffee and olives?
這組合不好
Bad combination.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
就是在這裡發生的  是不是  大俱樂部
This is where it's happening, right? The big club?
給  你的馬提尼  三顆橄欖
Here you go, martini, triple olives.
謝謝
Thanks.
勞蕾爾  回家吧
Laurel, go home.
西婭•奎恩告訴我
Thea Queen, telling me
夠了就是夠了
enough is enough.
現在有錢了
Now that is rich.
好吧
Fine.
取消我進你酒吧的資格
Bar me from your bar.
這是今天的主題  是嗎
That's today's theme, right?
取消資格
Disbarment.
勞蕾爾  你被取消律師資格了嗎
Laurel, are you being disbarred?
是的  看起來我的律師生涯結束了
Yeah, looks like my law career's over.
但你知道嗎
But you know what?
或許西婭可以雇我當服務員
Maybe Thea here can hire me as a waitress.
或者  奧利  我可以給你當秘書
Or, Ollie, I could come be your secretary.
但這意味著你要解雇她
But that would mean you would have to fire her.
你好  勞蕾爾  你還好嗎
Hi, Laurel. How are you?
你要借我的車嗎
Did you need to borrow my car?
你的豪車壞了嗎
Did your limo break down?
請幫她叫輛計程車
Get her a cab, please.
指紋在國際刑警數據庫有
Fingerprint was in Interpol's database.
那傢伙是米洛•阿米蒂奇的手下
The guy worked for Milo Armitage.
他是個黑市軍火商
He's a black market arms merchant.
他想賣掉那儀器
He's trying to sell the device.
你去找找阿米蒂奇
I need you to search for any indication
在星城的任何蛛絲馬跡
that Armitage is in Starling.
已經找了  他的船在星城碼頭
I already did. His ship filed a loading manifest
提交了一張裝貨單
at the Starling City docks.
我會把船號給你
I'll get you the slip number.
你好  我是奧利弗
Hi, it's Oliver.
我剛剛碰到勞蕾爾  她出事了
I just ran into Laurel, and something's wrong.
她需要你
She needs you.
斯萊德
Slade?
奧利弗
Oliver...
斯萊德
Slade!
回來
Get back!
我們知道你的目標是那艘船
We know you're targeting the boat.
我要把那混蛋
I'm going to send that son of a bitch
送到海底
to the bottom of the ocean.
你要毀掉我們離開這個島的唯一出路
You're going to destroy our only way off of the island!
只要艾沃死了  那就行
As long as Ivo is dead, it's fine.
我不能讓你這麼做
I can't let you do it.
後退  不然就幫我
Get back, or so help me,
我會放到你的
I will put you down!
媽媽  你在這兒幹什麼
Mom? What are you doing here?
我來徵求一下你的意見
I came by to get your advice on something.
到我辦公室來
Step into my office.
是選舉的事  是不是
This is about the campaign, right?
你能想到參與這事非常的棒
It's really awesome you're thinking of doing this.
你說的某些話我一直揮之不去
You said something that stayed with me.
可能外面有投票人
The idea that there could be voters out there
不會立刻就讓我卸任
that wouldn't dismiss me out of hand.
你的確經營著一家數十億美元的公司
Well, you did run a multi-billion dollar company.
是啊  還做了一件毀了城市的事
Yes, and an undertaking that destroyed the city.
人們會慢慢忘記的
People will get over that.
你怎麼能這麼確定
What makes you so certain?
因為我就是
Because I did.
我能提個建議嗎
Can I make a suggestion?
不要再因為覺得自己毀了城市而自責
Instead of punishing yourself because you think you destroyed the city,
開始著手拯救這城市怎麼樣
how about you start by saving it?
一千萬美元
$10 million,
我想這是說好的價格
I believe was the negotiated amount.
恭喜  你現在進入新的納稅階層了
Congratulations, you're now in a new tax bracket.
只是出於好奇
Just out of curiosity,
你付給我一千萬美元  那你能得到...
you pay me ten million, and you get...
這價錢的三倍
Three times that.
你已經有買家了
You already have a buyer?
我建議你遠離馬庫維亞幾個月
I recommend that you stay clear of Markovia for a few months.
我想我們的生意到此結束了
I believe our business is now concluded.
還沒有
Not yet.
看起來你的搭檔拋棄你了
Looks like your partner abandoned you.
他不是我的搭檔
He's not my partner.
他是我雇來做事的
He's someone I hired to do a job.
看來這筆錢花的值
And it turns out it was money well spent.
趴下太愚蠢了
Just too dumb to stay down.
別那麼做
Don't do it!
你會殺死這裡的所有人
You'll kill everyone here.
如果我不把這儀器送到馬庫維亞的買家手裡
If I don't deliver this device to my buyer in Markovia,
我也一樣死定了
I'm dead anyway.
不
No!
羅伊  我需要你的幫助
Roy, I need your help.
羅伊  馬上住手
Roy, stop right now!
-羅伊  -混蛋
- Roy. - Son of bitch.
羅伊  羅伊  住手
Roy! Roy, I need you to stop!
地震儀器就在裡面
The earthquake device is in there.
這鋼是軍事級別的  能抵擋炸彈
The steel is military grade; it's built to withstand a bomb,
但是抵擋不了你
but not you.
想想西婭
Think about Thea.
如果沒有你的幫助  她可能會死
Because she could die without your help.
我知道你愛她...
I know you love her...
因為我看見了
Because I've seen it.
救救我的妹妹
Save my sister.
控制住
Control.
集中注意力想西婭
Focus on Thea.
她現在需要你
She needs you right now,
否則她就會死
or she is dead.
所有人都會死
Everyone is dead.
你是...
You're...
對  沒錯
Yeah. Yeah.
去年  你救了我的命
Last year, you saved my life.
我不是說從綁架我的人手裡
And I don't mean from the guy who kidnapped me.
我是說  你...
I mean, you...
你拯救了我
you saved me.
你給了我目標
You gave me purpose.
我們才剛剛開始
We're just getting started.
所以...秘密組織有了個新成員
So...the secret society gets a new member.
他現在在哪
Where is he now?
在家
Home.
他還在...
He's, uh...
消化這事
processing.
當我知道你的真實身份時
When I found out who you really were,
我吃了一品脫的薄荷片才接受這個事實
I processed my way through a pint of mint chip.
我壓力大就吃東西
I stress eat.
說到壓力...
Speaking of stress...
我不是想開周一例會  今天週三
I'm not trying to Monday morning quarterback here--it's Wednesday.
這一切不都是因為你擔心
Didn't this all start because you were worried
羅伊的力量會被壞人利用嗎
that Roy's marble collection was on the short side?
她說得有理  奧利弗
She has a point, Oliver.
羅伊是匹野馬  現在他知道你的秘密了
Roy's a loose cannon. Now he knows your secret.
你說得對
You're right,
但我沒考慮後果
and I wasn't thinking about the consequences.
我只知道我需要他的力量
I only knew that I needed his strength.
他的力量
His power.
在島上
On the island,
莎拉告訴我愛是最強大的情感
Sara told me that love is the most powerful emotion.
綠箭俠不能讓羅伊想到西婭
Well, the Arrow couldn't get Roy to think about Thea.
但我可以
But I could.
我說了後退
I said get back!
想想莎朵
Think about Shado.
我在...
I am...
想著她
thinking about her!
我得告訴你一件關於莎朵的事
There's something I have to tell you about Shado.
是一件你需要知道的事
It's something you deserve to know.
她愛你  斯萊德
She loved you, Slade.
也許不是以你想要的方式
Maybe not the way that you wanted her to,
但她愛你
but she loved you.
而且她想讓你回家
And she wanted you to make it home.
她想讓你再見到喬
She wanted you to see Joe again.
她想讓你擁抱你的兒子
She wanted you to hug your son.
我知道你很憤怒
I know you're angry.
我也知道你想復仇
And I know you want revenge.
如果你毀了艾沃的貨船
If you destroy Ivo's freighter,
莎朵就白白犧牲了
Shado will have died for nothing.
我到底怎麼了
What is happening to me?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不會讓你一個人
I am not going to let you go through it
承受這些的
on your own.
殺了莎朵的那個人
The man who killed Shado
還沒被抓到
is still out there.
而不管那艘貨船沉沒沒有
And whether that freighter's on the bottom of the ocean or not,
我們都還被困在這個島上
we're still stuck on this island.
不會很久的
Not for long.
因為我們要乘那艘貨船回家
Because we're going to take the freighter.
很高興收到你的郵件
I was glad to receive your email.
是不是跟我想的一樣
Does it portend what I'm hoping?
我要去參加競選
I'm going to run.
是什麼讓你改變主意的
What changed your mind?
西婭
Thea.
她提醒我我還欠這座城市的
She reminded me that I still owe this city.
我想被世人銘記  而不是作為
And I want to be remembered as something more
馬爾科姆•梅林的傀儡
than Malcolm Merlyn's pawn.
你應該被人記住
As you should.
但你知道我的猶豫還有別的原因
But you know there was another reason for my reticence.
你害怕別人知道
You're afraid the people will learn
羅伯特不是她的親生父親
that Robert wasn't her biological father.
我設法在不說出
I managed to get through a
真相的情況下通過了審判
criminal trial without the truth coming out,
但政治選舉能更容易地挖出
but political campaigns tend to be a bit more adept
一個人罪惡的秘密
at extracting skeletons from closets.
但沒有別人知道
But no one else knows.
有人知道
Someone does.
我的婦產科醫生  吉爾醫生
My OB, Dr. Gill.
西婭出生時情況很複雜
There were complications when Thea was born,
我不得不告訴他羅伯特不是她父親
And I had to tell him that Robert wasn't her father.
如果我們要發展下去
If we're going to move forward,
我們得確定
we need to make certain
他不會成為我們的問題
that he won't be a problem for us.
特納先生
Mr. Turner.
我不知道這裡還允許配偶探視
I didn't know this place allowed conjugal visits.
我叫阿曼達•沃勒
My name is Amanda Waller.
你說的好像你很有名
You say that like it's supposed to mean something.
正好相反
To the contrary.
我的身份是高度機密
My identity is highly classified.
那你為什麼向我做自我介紹
Then why are you introducing yourself to me?
我有個工作機會給你
I have an offer for you.
一個讓你減刑的方法
A way to work off your sentence.
事實證明  我需要一個像你一樣...
As it turns out, I have need of someone with your...
天賦異稟的人
singular qualifications.
為了什麼
For what?
為了一支我正在組建的部隊
For a unit I'm putting together.
什麼樣的部隊
What type of unit?
實際上...
Actually...
更像是一支小隊
It's more of a squad.
我知道了你的秘密你會殺了我嗎
Is this the part where you kill me 'cause I know your secret?
你覺得我會殺了我妹妹的男朋友嗎
Do you actually think that I'd kill my sister's boyfriend?
可你曾經往我腿上射了一箭
Well, you did shoot me in the leg.
不過我已經原諒你了
Forgiven, by the way.
西婭
Thea.
永遠不能讓她知道
She can never know.
我覺得如果我告訴她的話
I get the feeling that if I did tell her,
你真的會殺了我
that would be when you kill me.
相信你的直覺
Trust that instinct.
好吧
Ok. All right.
有多少人知道
How many people know what--
你是誰
who you are?
很多
Too many.
但只有這兩個比較重要
But these are the only two that matter.
約翰•狄格爾和費利西蒂•斯莫克
John Diggle and Felicity Smoak.
這個團隊有名字嗎
Does this group have a name?
比如綠箭隊之類的
Like Team Arrow, or something?
我們不那麼稱呼自己
We don't call ourselves that.
我會  偶爾會
I do. Occasionally.
-停  -無所謂
- Stop.  - Whatever.
歡迎加入
Welcome aboard.
莎拉...
Sara...